# ADRIENNE HODGES adrienne.m.hodges@gmail.com • 843-367-0068

I'm a Graphic Designer with four years experience creating and maintaining brand identities across print and digital media. Because design and web development go hand-in-hand, I'm excited to be continuing my creative education in Front-End Development at Charleston Code Camp. I have a passion for creating awesome user experiences, both for print and digital, and I love taking the creative and problem-solving skills I use as a designer and applying those to web development.

## **PORTFOLIO**

DESIGN PORTFOLIO SITE • adriennehodges.squarespace.com

DESIGN AND WEB DEVELOPMENT SITE • currently designing and building • adriennehodges.github.io

# **EDUCATION**

CODECAMP CHARLESTON • Front-End Development • AUG 2014 - PRESENT

A.A. IN GRAPHIC DESIGN • Art Institute of Charleston • SEPT 2010

B.A. IN POLITICAL SCIENCE AND SPANISH • Furman University • Magna cum laude • JUN 2006

## **EXPERIENCE**

# LEAD DESIGNER AND PROJECT MANAGER • FEB 2014-PRESENT

Bison Branding, Charleston, SC

Lead Designer and Creative Marketing Account Manager for LimRic Plumbing, Heating, and Air

Coordinate fleet vehicle wrap projects from inception to final product delivery to optimize workflow and resources In-house branding for print and web design for Bison Branding

Design for wide range of clients to communicate brand message across print and digital media

Design for custom WordPress sites

#### GRAPHIC DESIGNER AND PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT DESIGNER • MAR 2011-FEB 2014

MVP Group International, Charleston, SC

Lead Designer for Febreze Home Collection • Lead comprehensive brand re-design • website design and copywriting

Designed and lead new product development for Febreze Home Collection

Designed candle and home fragrance collections specific to private label brands' target customers

## GREEN ION DESIGN INTERN • JUN 2010-DEC 2010

Blue Ion, Charleston, SC

Collaborated with creative team and clients on designs for websites and collateral materials

# TELLER AND TRANSLATOR FOR SPANISH-SPEAKING CUSTOMERS • FEB 2008-MAR 2011

Bank of America, Charleston, SC

Gained valuable customer service and communication skills with diverse clientele

## ENGLISH LANGUAGE AND CULTURE AUXILIARY IN BILINGUAL SCHOOL • OCT 2006-DEC 2007

Nuestra Señora de Fátima Bilingual Elementary School, Madrid, Spain

Organized language and cultural learning activities and designed and made materials to facilitate English learning Obtained teaching skills that enable me to adapt content to communicate efficiently with various audiences

# WEB DEVELOPMENT COURSEWORK

## WEB BASICS FIVE COURSE SERIES • WEB 101-105 • CODE CAMP CHARLESTON

HTML and CSS syntax and styling

JavaScript and JQuery

Fundamentals of programming languages • syntax, variables, loops, arrays, functions, classes, and condition statements Basic PHP to connect front-end to back-end and back-end troubleshooting

GitHub • how to create, clone, push, commit, and work with GitHub through the command line

# INTRO TO OBJECT ORIENTED PROGRAMMING • CODE CAMP CHARLESTON

Four main principles of object oriented programming languages

PHP, database creation, manipulation, and form manipulation as introduction to backend development

# **SKILLS**

Adobe Creative Suite HTML CSS JavaScript jQuery PHP Project Management

## **HONORS**

"Most Innovative" Award for Febreze Home Collection candle labels at Procter & Gamble Product Design Expo Design chosen for cover of 2009-2010 Student Handbook for The Art Institute of Charleston Member Phi Beta Kappa National Honor Society